<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on kees.online</title>
    <link>https://kees.online/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on kees.online</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 20:53:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kees.online/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I didn’t donate 500 euros a weekday to my anti charity</title>
      <link>https://kees.online/post/how-i-didnt-donate-500-euros-a-weekday-to-my-anti-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 20:53:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kees.online/post/how-i-didnt-donate-500-euros-a-weekday-to-my-anti-charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love how sports make me feel. Every time I do some, I end up energized and happy. Even with this in mind, I used to fail miserably in actually doing sports. Making time to do them, with distractions like Netflix in reach, often seemed to require more will power than I could provide. And even when I did make the time, I found it very hard to actually step outside into the cold to start running. Strange, because I know I enjoy going for a jog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took many tries and many years to overcome this strange gap between what I knew I liked doing but what I didn’t like starting. As of this year I finally found a way to keep myself motivated. And it works: I have been running for the last 28 weekdays in a row and lost 6.6 kilograms in the process. I’m eager to share my strategy with you so you may benefit from it as well!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom endomondo email reports</title>
      <link>https://kees.online/post/create-custom-endomondo-email-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 19:53:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kees.online/post/create-custom-endomondo-email-reports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the year 2010 I’ve used the app Endomondo to track all of my (462) runs. To improve my odds of  succeeding at my personal challenge of running 1 kilometer every weekday (or pay 500 euros to my anti charity), I decided to create a motivating weekly report that gets sent to my email every Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, with Endomondo not providing a public API, this wasn’t as easy as it could have been. I got creative and found another way to access the activity data. If you follow the steps in this article, you too will be able to create reports like the one below. No technical background required!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>